[Music]
w
hello good evening good day everybody
and welcome back to the ask abijit show
after a break of a week I was traveling
last weekend so apologies for not doing
a live stream last weekend but here we
are back again A lot has happened and I
hope you're all doing very well let me
first of all see who all is there on the
live chat firstly I would like to thank
B N ningombam geopolitical dub and
harthala for purchasing a membership I
really appreciate that I never ever ask
anyone to buy this but you all still do
this so thank you so much I really
appreciate that now let's see who all is
there on the live chat I can see
sanatani Sagar pritam Sharma DJ Singh
pulkit grower sparkling Lotus buan so
ran Kapil crazy brain good evening
Ashish mayri Krishna
discombobulation Prav
jadav meang kitang kbon from the Far
East of India Namaste bishwajit L Chan
sahil Anri
ramachandra hey
iswar Max gaming Shani T kadamba guy
chattan aradya Yip
Abad starlord kapalin rishikesh
utar misc Vladimir vladimirovich Putin
random skull uh deas surra abishek Pandi
ainka Paar by by K rajat Verma kixo kixo
abishek s tanay Chandra s Satish VI
Singh shagun Chopra good to see you
ma'am Slayer a AR arish two idiot nris
fairy tale supratim data Jagdish Mali oh
home Kiker soic banery an motion Clips
VVS 2400 DHA
plays Baba Abhijit Chava der Kaiser
Alvin Rodriguez grimo
bad uh and so many other people I won't
be able to greet you all individually
apologies but thank you so much all of
you for being on this live stream so uh
I'm sure everybody wants to talk about
the big big thing so let's see what what
uh what are the questions we have I'm
going to take questions from the from
the comments that you the questions that
you've asked in the comments and then if
there is time I'll take questions from
the live chat as well let's take some
quick questions first of all uh why
don't you take questions from live chat
these days because I want to answer the
best possible questions see lots of
times what happens is that when you're
doing a taking questions from the live
chat you don't always get the best
possible questions you often I often get
questions that I've answered lots of
lots of times I see first of all
understand please understand no question
is stupid no question is bad I am happy
to answer all questions but there are
some questions I've answered over and
over again like when are we taking back
po what if the British or the or the
Turks never invaded India and so on some
questions that are standard questions
everybody has them especially new me new
viewers and I've answered them in the
first 10 20 30 episodes of askit so you
know during a live live if I'm taking
questions from a live stream I typically
get a lot of those so it's hard for me
to find really good questions that will
really give value to all of you that's
why I prefer to take questions from the
comments okay next
question uh are you hacked why are you
live streaming for seven days straight
so once again that's in connection to
the question I just answered I have done
so many live streams and there are so
many questions I've answered that I
would prefer not to take them again and
I would prefer to take questions about
that are relevant to what's happening
right now and more important things in
the world but I've answered all kinds of
questions in the past so I'm just
putting out old episodes on a loop on
two live streams one is the history and
geopolitics live stream and another one
is the Science episode science physics
astrophysics all that stuff two live
streams going on anybody who wants to
watch go ahead and watch watch as as
long as much time as you have and you
may get uh answers to questions that you
may have uh so it's it's there's nothing
wrong with the channel when somebody
gets hacked it's typically something bad
that happens
right so I am running these live streams
on a loop like a bunch of episodes
together 20 30 40 episodes on a lop so
that whoever wants to watch can check
out the old live streams so so many
wonderful questions you all have asked
in the past and I've answered them so
you'll get to see those over there so
there's no issue it's still going on
right now there are three live streams
on the channel including this one which
is an actual live
stream
okay right here we are
my views on the Trump and zinsky meeting
looks like the special military
operation is going to end Amisha says
what exactly happened between Trump and
zinski what led to the situation
zilinsky was thrown out of the White
House this is crazy uh zilinski was
lambasted in Silence by Trump and JD
vans on air live on air yesterday if
zinski has any shame left he should
resign with dignity the more he delays
and continues this his comedic crant the
more Troublesome his fall from his reign
will be what's your take on his future
will he escape to any of the European
countries as he has to relinquish power
post Seas fire possibly this year
okay yesterday was incredible what
happened right
um there was this live press briefing
from the O office in the in the White
House you have President Trump and
zilinski sitting in these two chairs and
to president Trump's left you have J van
the vice president and Marco Rubio the
Secretary of State to the right of
zinsky you have some Ukrainian and the
whole room is f with filled with media
people and this is about 45 50 minutes
long the entire video that you can find
on on social
media um initially what happened is that
you you got these little clips that came
out of of this entire you know blow up
that happened uh zalinski and Trump
shout essentially shouting at at each
other talking over each other JD van
intervening and and it was horrific to
watch and it and it looked like zilinski
was ambushed and they brought him there
to to humiliate him or to uh give him a
dressing down that's how it looked right
but then if you watch the entire video
the 45 50 minute video you will see that
zalinsky started this all this entire
matter he was being rude
disrespectful he was looking for a fight
you know there are you know you'll find
in life sometimes some people are high
drugs or high on alcohol and they go out
there on the streets or wherever they go
looking for a fight they're looking for
a fight zinsky looked like that he
looked like he was high on something
some some substance and he had come
there looking for a
fight and he was
provoking both Trump and JD van and
Trump stayed calm as long as it could
and then at some point zalinski starts
uh pointing at JD van and saying that if
you raise your voice it's not going to
make you right and that sort of
thing how disrespectful can you be to
your hosts and especially when your host
is the most powerful nation in the world
and especially after the fact that
zilinski is
alive because of the support he has
received the past three years or three
years plus from the United States and
NATO right it was crazy it was
incredible the guy zilinski seems to
have lost it incredibly rude and
disrespectful the most powerful country
in the world the most powerful president
or or Head of State in the world you
don't disrespect that
guy oh man so uh this situation was
caused by
zilinski uh he was essentially trying to
negotiate a deal live in front of the
cameras you don't do that live in front
of the cameras whatever diplomat
negotiations you want to do you do it
behind closed doors when you go to the
old office and you have the cameras in
front of you you have to behave with a
certain amount of dignity and you have
to be tactful and diplomatic when the
cameras are ruling you you know what we
saw yesterday was what happens what
generally happens behind closed doors
behind closed doors you can yell at each
other negotiate push push back bully
whatever you want to do you don't do
that when the cameras are rolling you
got to see something that generally
happens that always happens behind
closed
doors that's that's a first I've never
seen that we I have been telling you for
the past three years as long as this
show has been going on the ask show that
behind closed doors diplomacy is all
about hard power it's about arm twisting
it's about bullying it's about
ultimatums it's it's there's nothing
nice about diplomacy behind closed doors
but we saw that yesterday with the
cameras ruling and zinsky was trying was
he tried his best
to to
to disrespect his hosts and there came a
point where Trump trump said enough is
enough and he was trying he came there
with with an agenda he came there with
demands you don't make demands when you
have zero Leverage What leverage does
zinsky
have absolutely nothing he is he is
living and breathing at the
pleasure of the president of the United
States the moment funding and support
stops he's dead man
walking uh so um it looks like there was
some kind of instigation from the EU
Nations as well because the moment this
happens like a whole bunch of completely
insignificant and irrelevant EU leaders
put out the same tweet supporting
zilinski uh interesting interesting
thing very interesting thing happened so
it looks like this is the beginning of
the end for Mr
zilinski unless the EU is willing to to
support him and ensure his safety and
survival the man is a quizzing the man
is a traitor to his own people and his
own Nation he has colluded with a
foreign power with the Biden
regime uh
and participated in the destruction of
his nation's
demography his nation's Human Resources
his na nation's wealth his nation's
infrastructure his nation's sovereignty
his nation's Prosperity his nation's
future that's what he has
done that man is that's that's what a
quizzing is vikun quizzing was the
original quizzing and he did not meet a
very good end zalinski is a quizzing
he's going to go down in history as a
traitor to his people and his nation and
it generally doesn't end well for such
people so yes eventually Trump said
enough is enough and uh the meeting
ended and there was supposed to be the
signing of of a deal the the minerals uh
the mineral wealth deal uh in which
Ukraine would hand over its mineral
wealth essentially to the US because of
all the wealth the US has expended in uh
in in uh supporting Ukraine the past
three years so that deal did not happen
it was not signed and zalinsky and his
and his uaj were asked to leave the
White House they were essentially kicked
out thrown out of the White House like
Amisha says down here uh and I don't
blame Trump or JD van for what happened
it was entirely zilinski is doing so
yeah incredible scenes yesterday
life is Meaningful says zalinski abuses
wi US wice president in front of trump
in the White House you think zinski is
the worst capable leader or even
Diplomat for any country so yes Mr
zinski did he was caught on camera on
audio
abusing uh J
Vance he used a Russian word not as
Ukrainian word Russian word Suka which
is a naughty word in the Russian
language I'll just say that much okay so
he uses a Russian swear word under his
breath but it was caught on audio he use
that word for JD Vance his host the vice
president of the United States what sort
of a person does that I just don't get
it that you cannot I cannot think of any
worst head of state in the world right
now of course zinsky is not a
democratically elected person he's a
dictator like Trump has said I said that
a year ago zalinski
uh he is now a dictator I think there
was supposed to be according to the
Ukrainian Constitution an election at a
whether it was March or June or whatever
last year and beyond that zalinsky was
in power illegitimately
unconstitutionally so he's a
dictator and he's been propped up
by by the US essentially and he goes to
the White House and he calls JD van Suka
incredible incredible person
uh okay the priest of Varanasi has two
questions how long could Ukraine survive
if Donald Trump completely cuts off the
US Aid given to them can Europe
collectively save them why did zinski
not accept the peace treaty proposed by
Donald Trump when Ukraine is in a weak
negotiating State what would happen if
the US cuts off military aid to Ukraine
after this the US is Trump is I am
pretty sure in the process of cutting
off all a to Ukraine I'm sure some
announcements have already been made I'm
not going to go and look into the
details right now because we are in a
live stream right now but yes the
process has started Trump is going to
cut off Aid Ukraine see Trump came to
power with a number of promises he made
a number of promises right one of the
promises is that he was going to end the
Ukraine war essentially the first day of
of his presidency has said it's been a
bit longer than that people understand
it takes time but he's already
made the moves and and taken actions
that and reached out to Putin and spoken
with Putin on the phone Etc and the
process of the end game of the Ukraine
war is already in in motion so Trump is
keeping his promise right and the only
question then is that what happens to
Ukraine what terms does Ukraine get get
what happens to zinski which is not that
important Ukraine is more important not
zinski so
essentially the fate of Ukraine will be
decided by Trump and
Putin zinski is not a legitimate leader
he's a dictator he's a
puppet he's a puppet of the US and
puppets don't get to make choices and he
has no leverage over anyone he is alive
and breathing at the pleasure of his
master his htic master the US uh so look
what's going to happen now is Trump has
no interest anymore in talking with
zilinski
he made it very clear that we can't do
business with this attitude of yours
that's what he told zinski and uh so
what's going to happen now is that Trump
and Putin are going to have uh round of
discussions uh their minions
subordinates like the secretary of state
of the US Rubio and Sergey lvov of of
Russia they will
meet multiple times and they're going to
negotiate the parameters of the of the
ceasefire and Putin is going to get what
he
wants uh he's going to get he's going to
keep the territories his uh nation has
conquered from Ukraine and a number of
other things and I'm sure the end game
the deal between the US and Russia will
include the expulsion from power of
volodimir
zalinski uh I'm pretty sure so it's
almost like I'm making a prediction here
um why did zilinski not accept this
because it it's the the end for him then
right why is he relevant today because
the media has propped him up has
lionized him as this great defender of
Ukraine right he's relevant in the world
today because the war is going on the
moment the war ends his relevance
legitimacy everything
ends so he wants this war to keep going
on and the EU leaders also seem to want
this war to keep going
on um because um their legitimacy also
is to some extent tied to the war and
the choices they have made in the past
three years tie them to the fate of of
of
zalinski uh so Ukraine is not in a weak
negotiating State Ukraine has zero
leverage Ukraine has no more uh say in
its eventual fate and destiny so so the
US will essentially cut off Aid to
Ukraine if the EU wants to step in and
give some Aid we'll see how that goes it
won't end very nicely for for whoever
does that in the U as well I don't think
Europe can collectively save Ukraine uh
I'm sure they can give some money to
Ukraine but what about the arms and
ammunition that Ukraine needs to keep
fighting the war does Europe have any of
that they don't have much of that uh
does France want
to spend a significant amount of his GDP
propping up Zeland and continuing this
war which has no real uh benefit for
anyone I don't think so it doesn't make
any sense economically so Ukraine will
not survive once Donald Trump cuts off
Aid so the eventual fate of Ukraine is
going to be decided by Donald Trump and
Vladimir Putin Donald Trump has no
interest in the war Putin knew that he
just needs to keep the war going I've
said this so many times it's it's been a
slow War scenario it's been a frozen
Conflict by Design if Putin wanted he
could have flattened Ukraine he chose
not to because there's no point doing
that right and so on so yeah that's the
situation right
now PR Paul says Trump tells zalinski
that without US military aid the war
could would have ended in two weeks and
accuses him of gambling with the lives
of millions and risking World War II is
Trump right about the gambling part has
Western support prolong the war rather
than securing a resolution what do I
think Trump is absolutely right without
US military aid without the spares
without the supplies without the arms
ammunition the javelins what what not
the Americans have Supply the tanks um
and so on Ukraine would not have lasted
two weeks zinsky said that Trump is
echoing Putin and uh Ukraine would not
have lasted three
days you know even with us Aid Putin
could have flattened Ukraine he simply
did not use his Air Force except using
it very
sparingly and and whatever argument some
people want to make they're going to
fall flat today I've been saying the
same thing the past three years and
today's situation vindicates what I've
been seeing the past three years uh
Putin's Air Force is intact he has
barely used it just a few Suk here and
there older versions a few helicopters
very little uh if he had if Putin had
chosen he could have flattened destroyed
Ukraine in in less than three weeks in
less than two weeks uh so yes Trump is
absolutely
correct uh without US military there's
no way Ukraine would have lasted three
years let alone let alone three weeks
now why did put why did Trump say that
zilinsky has been gambling with the
lives of millions in risking World War I
you may
remember during the Jakarta G 20 Summit
which was in 2022 in the last quarter of
2022 the
ukrainians uh they launched a missile
into polish I think polish territory in
Poland and struck a village and it
caused at least a one or two casualties
deaths of Polish citizens and then they
they blamed Russia for this the
ukrainians zinski and his commanders
knew that they had launched the missile
but they blamed Russia for it to invoke
one of the Clauses in the NATO treaty
that if one NATO member is attacked
everybody has to respond so he was
trying to launch World War II right
there
zilinski right he's been doing that
consistently he's gambling with the
lives of millions he's he has tried his
best to spark off World War I multiple
times I'm just giving you one
example look it up during the jakata
summit
G20 Summit in
2022 he tried that he tried this he
tried to pull the stunt uh so yeah Trump
is right about the gambling part
zilinski has been gambling with the
lives of millions he's been trying to
spark off World War
II um and Western support has simply
prolonged the war what's the
resolution Russia get Russia is going to
retain the territories it took in 2022
itself and after then it's been a slow
Meandering War so Trump is absolutely
right absolutely
right geopolitical dub and PR Paul ask
these questions why are the EU countries
which are heavily affected by this
Ukraine war why are the supporting
zalinski uh whereas the US has well
lectured zilinski yesterday and with
European leaders and even us politicians
rallying behind Ukraine after Trump's
meeting with zalinski what will this
actually change everything on the ground
or is this just perforative outrage good
question also given Trump's recent
actions do you think he's aligning more
openly with Putin and Russia excellent
questions uh yeah we we're trying to go
into the mindset and and and uh why are
things being done and why are these
decisions being taken by so and so
people so um look we have to understand
what is how do we analyze what's
happening I mean EU leaders like you
mentioned are supporting they're
rallying out rallying behind zalinski a
whole bunch of EU leaders have put out
these tweets Etc uh I'm not sure if I
can look it up right now but like large
number of irrelevant insignificant EU
leaders have put out Tweets in support
of zki even some American politicians
and so
on um so does this change anything on
the ground or is this just performative
Outreach that's a great question you see
a
tweet if you know me if you are a
longtime follower of the ask you TR you
will know that I keep on emphasizing
that there's a s there's a gigantic
difference between words and
actions right words don't matter the
only thing that matters is your
actions a
tweet is verbal
support right what verbal support oh I I
support you yeah yeah bat on the back I
support you but are they going to
actually support him on the ground are
they going to you know send money and
send weapons and are they even capable
of sending weapons and
money so clearly this is performative
Outreach this is a performative
performance essentially it changes
nothing on the ground can the EU Nations
together muster up sufficient
money on an ongoing B basis and
sufficient weapons and arms and
ammunition on an ongoing basis to keep
the war going they
can't this is called virtue
signaling and
uh so now let's look at what are the
interests of these of the major parties
in this entire matter we know what
Russia's interests are why did why did
the war begin because of NATO's
Relentless Eastward expansion and
eventually red lines were crossed and
Russia decided that we have no choice
but to ensure that Ukraine remains
neutral and we have no no choice but to
safeguard the Russian speaking
populations of Ukraine who are being
essentially uh massacred by by Ukraine
since
2014 uh the luhans donet regions Etc so
Russia waited as long as possible I
think they waited too long Putin should
have done this in 2014 itself after he
took Crimea but whatever uh so we know
what Russia's interests are Russia's
interest are the red lines cannot be
crossed or Ukraine cannot be a EU Nation
cannot be a NATO Nation you canot have
NATO boths on the ground in Ukraine and
Ukraine needs to be neutral nation and
Ukraine is historically part of Russia
and so on that's Russia's position and
they have secured their interests by
doing the military operation that's what
Putin has done Ukraine's interest today
is to continue to exist in some shape or
form and to that's one Ukraine's
interest first of all to continue to
exist it's an existential crisis now for
Ukraine secondly whatever population
they have left that needs to be
safeguarded the war has chewed up I
don't know how many hundreds of
thousands of Ukrainian young Ukrainian
men and even older Ukrainian men that's
a demographic disaster that needs to end
right this is somebody else's War it's a
proxy war the Americans are now saying
it openly it's been a proxy war I have
been saying this for three years
I was saying this when it was not
fashionable to say that today everyone
is saying it saying it it's a proxy war
so you what's the point of being
somebody's proxy and and the America the
Biden Administration was happy for the
war to go on as long as the last
Ukrainian was alive so Ukraine's
interests are sa to to continue to exist
in some shape of or form to retain some
territory whatever the Russians have not
taken thus far to end the war immed as
Seas fire as soon as possible so so that
no more ukrainians
die and hopefully to have a proper
leader who
actually works towards Ukraine's
National interest not somebody else's
interest which means there needs to be a
regime change in KV that's Ukraine's
interest but that's not zelinsky's
interest zin's interest is let the war
go on now what is the eu's interest in
all this from an EU perspective European
Union
perspective what they should look at
is their economies need to do better the
past three years their economies have
been kind of devastated they've not been
doing well the economic growth engine
has spluttered and and subsided many of
these economies have gone into
recession the From eu's perspective
their interest is that there needs to be
a resumption of the supply of cheap
energy from Russia to to to Europe so
that the economic growth engine can be
revived and they obviously from the
European perspective would want
assurances from Putin that he will not
expand further westwards Beyond
Ukraine and so on so the that's Europe's
interest the American interest is that
this war should end we need to stop
donating this money for this pointless
war and they want a reconfiguration of
their relationship with with the EU
nations with with the NATO Nations and
all and they will do that and the the
American interest is also to recuperate
as much uh money as possible from
Ukraine because they spent like I don't
know 300 400 billion dollars so they
will try and recuperate that through
Ukraine's mineral wealth so Ukraine is
essentially up for sale right now its
resources its territories are all going
to be divided up reminds me to some
extent of the end of the Ottoman
Empire I'm talking about what uh 1919
1920 around that time roughly roughly
given give or take a couple of years
that's of you know the Ottoman Empire
was essentially chopped up and parceled
out to various uh to the various winning
allies of the first world war Victorious
allies that sort of thing could happen
to Ukraine right now
so why are the EU Nations and leaders
trying to
uh verbally support zilinski see I'll
tell you
why uh Trump came to power for the first
time in 2016 you remember that and he
had a very um disastrous presidency he
was not able to get anything done not
even that wall that he wanted to build
with Mexico nothing the entire system
was was up against him his own party was
up against him and the entire so-called
deep state was very non-republican or
rather Democrat Democrat
in
nature and this is the Machinery deep
State Machinery that controls EU and
NATO so each EU see these EU
leaders they are not really
democratically elected They Don't Really
uh work towards the interests of their
Nations and people they are allowing an
immigration illegal immigration and so
many issues you have in in the EU so
these people they don't really
work towards the national interest
that's not that they they have other
interests and each of these leaders will
have an set of handlers American
handlers who tell them what to do and
what not to do and how to behave and
what things to say and what things
you're not supposed to say and what
policies you're supposed to adopt and
many of these policies most of these
policies come from Brussels which is the
headquarters of the European Union and
the boss of the
EU uh what's her name uh her name is
UHA V Lan she also will have a bunch of
handlers so all these handlers who tell
these people what to do are going to be
non-republican
oldtime Democrats essentially and they
don't like Trump that's why the EU
leaders also don't like Trump they are
much more comfortable with the uh
Democrats so there is this tussle going
on right now they are perfectly happy
working for the us but not for Trump
they want to oppose Trump so that's the
tug of war we are seeing right now but
they will not put their money and their
lives on the line to prop up zinski
they'll simply give him verbal support
and so on and maybe it is they who
instigated zilinsky to go to the White
House and create this gigantic
incident
um yeah so that's why they're supporting
the Ukrainian president and because they
themselves are are not really legitimate
leaders most of these EU people except a
few are not really legitimate leaders
maybe ma is legitimate because France is
a
quasi Sovereign Nation much more
Sovereign than the other EU
Nations yeah so that's a
deal tan Chandra says did you ever
imagine that Americans and Russians
along with North Koreans Israelis
belarusians will vote in the United
Nations and will be on the same side the
recent UNC voting on Ukraine Russia
conflict took Everyone by
surprise what should the Indian mea
Ministry of external Affairs do
according to me good question let's take
a look at the way the voting
happened let's pull this
up and let me put that on the
screen one
second let's put that on the screen so
this is what
happened yeah so this
vote uh for for this resolution happened
on the 24th of February today is the 1st
of March so it happened this Monday
today's Saturday and as you can see uh
number of nations voted against this
resolution which was a resolution to
condem the Russian invasion wh scale
Invasion and occupation of Ukraine and
that sort of language was used in the
resolution so who voted against Belarus
burkinafaso Burundi Central African
Republic DPR Korea which is North Korea
equatorial gine itria
hati uh Hungary Israel these are all
voting against Mali Marshal Islands
Nicaragua ner Pala Russian Federation
which is Putin Sudan and the United
States they all voted against so the US
was joined in opposing this resolution
by
Russia by
Israel in North Korea and India and
China and a large number of other
nations abstained the stayed out of this
matter they said this is none of our
business interesting isn't it so who
would have thought right like you say
that the US will side with with with
with North Korea and Russia along with
Israel and Belarus Etc in the United
Nations interesting isn't it one could
not have imagined this during the Biden
presidency but this is the Trump
presidency and Trump has Trump wants to
end the war and move forward uh and
that's why so so the resolution I think
called for Russia returning all the
territories to Ukraine obviously that's
not going to happen right Trump wants to
end the War he wants to end the war the
way it is right the way situation is
right now
uh so it did not really take me by
surprise even though overall it's
surprising that the US and Russia and
North Korea and
Israel Etc they vote on they vote
together in opposition to a certain
United Nations resolution and the EU
Nations UK Etc they vote in favor it's
so strange but yeah overall it's not
surprising but from a historical
perspective it's something that's really
unusual uh it's because Trump wants to
end the war and he knows the only way to
win end the war is to give Putin the
territorial gains he has already
acquired he's not going to give it up we
all know he's not not going to give it
up he can actually take more if he wants
if he feels like but he he probably only
wants the Russian speaking regions and
he will have a bunch of other demands
which most likely Trump will accept so
it's a vict for Russia that's
essentially what it is now the last last
part of the question is what should the
in Indian ministry of external Affairs
do
nothing we have been on the right side
of diplomacy we have been doing the
right things I must genuinely truly
commend India's position on this matter
the past three years India has taken all
the right decisions made all the right
choices India is going to end up on the
right side of history when it comes to
this
the beginning everybody was condemning
India especially in the west that India
will be on the wrong side of History
blah blah blah but look had
India uh participated in the sanctions
against Russia what would be what would
we look like today like idiots right so
everything we have done is right the
ministry of external Affairs is right to
abstain in these votes uh this is none
of our business uh we don't want to take
sides in this we urge peace we we call
upon everybody to end the war to have a
seire as soon as possible we want peace
again and that's what we we have been
consistently saying since the 22nd of
February
2022 so great going very good amazing
amazing performance amazing
job aanu and Sam Satish say what's
happening between the EU and the US we
all know what happened between Trump and
zilinski but if the EU is a vasal of the
US and why are they opposing the
president of the United States is the EU
trying to break free from us dominance
you were right when you told us that it
is Russia that's winning the war Trump
doesn't want this war to continue he
excluded Europe from peace talks but is
the EU trying to Shield Ukraine or is it
powerful enough to stand against the US
and what's the future of
Ukraine right so there is friction
between the EU and the United States I
mean the EU I've always said this and it
still stands true that the real power in
Europe there are two main major powers
in Europe in the East you have Russia in
the west you have the us the real power
in Western Europe is the US it's not EU
or the NATO or
NATO and the the US
physically occupies militarily occupies
a number of European nations including
the UK including Germany including uh
Italy um and the US has nuclear weapons
there are more there are more Nations I
just gave you a few the US has nuclear
weapons installed in various EU
Nations uh so the US is the real
military force and economic power in
Western Europe now right now what you're
seeing is politics okay all these EU
leaders they have a close Affinity with
the Democrats the Democratic Party in
the US and they don't they don't like
Trump and
uh that's that's the cause of the
friction and Trump wants the EU Nations
to spend more money towards the upkeep
of NATO a significantly higher
percentage of their
GDP for uh towards NATO should be given
by the EU Na by by the NATO Nations and
so on there are a number of uh points
sticking points in the relationship and
that's why these nations the these
leaders don't like Donald Trump and they
want to uh Stick it to him essentially
by supporting zilinski in this matter um
it's not going to be easy for Trump to
get these people in line but at the end
of the day he's the US president and
he's got the full might of the US
establishment behind him this
time he has certain things he needs to
do at home also like for example uh he
wanted to his administration wanted to
release the EP
files but they were given redacted
documents and not the full set of
evidence right the FBI is not
cooperating so there are still uh hold
over from the Ona regime the old old
regime of Biden the Democrats who
generally have been very
deeply uh in power in the establishment
and right now Trump has to do a cleanup
job so it's going to be difficult for
people like cash Patel who is the
director of the FBI
for people like Tuli gabard who is the
overall boss of the intelligence
agencies U you know
they have been put in this position that
you are the captain of the ship but the
entire significant portion of of the
crew is against them so it's a period of
transition it's going to be it's going
to take time for them to truly take the
Reign of Power it's going to be a period
of time so even with the EU leaders
Trump and his Secretary of State and the
overall foreign Min uh State Department
is going to have to work on them
um so yeah that's what's happening
between the EU and the US uh some people
some analysts are claiming the US is
withdrawing from Europe and becoming
more insular and so on I don't I would I
would not be uh so Hasty in making that
claim uh no superpower no Empire gives
up its Leverage so
easily but things are a flaw right now
in the world a lot is changing
especially from a technological
perspective the US has its hand on super
weapons super technologies that nobody
knows about it's all behind closed doors
uh I'm talking about AI obviously AI is
super intelligence
right I'm pretty sure they've achieved
ASI artificial super intelligence so
they don't need to you know physically
control so much of the planet right now
and so things are are changing we'll see
how it goes uh but yeah that's the
situation so these EU leaders they want
this war to be prolonged they want the
war to continue so that they remain
relevant but it's going to destroy the
economy of Europe in the long run so all
these leaders uh are problematic I mean
they don't really have the best interest
of their people and their countries in
mind otherwise they would not have
brought in so many illegal immigrants
and allowed the economy to deteriorate
so so badly and the UK would not have
allowed all those Pakistani grooming
gangs to to to violate their daughters
and so on these leaders don't really
care about their people the EU is a a is
a scam essentially so that's the deal
right
now Indian stock picker says it's very
obvious that Ukraine is not getting a
good deal over recent interactions
between Trump zinski and
Putin uh if Mr zalinski deals directly
uh with Mr Putin is there a chance for
Ukraine to be in a better position than
where it is now I mean no further gains
for the US uh at least they'll have uh
what all resources left to themselves
and Ukraine remains unexploited further
look Ukraine is in no position to
dictate what kind of deal it gets please
understand that uh let me bring a a
tweet of Mr Trump to to to your
attention Okay uh where can I find the
Tweet okay here it is I'm going to put
that on the screen briefly you know yeah
here we
are
shares okay here is the treat by Mr
Donald Trump it's a tweet from
2013 and this is what he said Remember
the golden rule of negotiating he who
has the gold makes the
rules this this is wisdom these are
words of wisdom by Mr Donald Trump he
who has the gold makes the rules now
does Ukraine have the gold Ukraine has
zero leverage of any kind and that's
why Ukraine is in no position to decide
what kind of deal it gets obviously it's
going to get a poor deal it's a helpless
Nation their president is apparently a
drug addict who thinks he can go and be
rude with everybody in the world he's
been rude with lots of EU leaders he's
been rude with Mr Modi when Mr Modi
visited Ukraine uh and Mr Putin can't
stand zilinski the two have history
they've met many times Mr zalinski has
been caught on camera mocking and
laughing at Mr Putin when Mr Putin was U
giving a
speech
um so there's no question of Mr zalinski
having the option of dealing at this
point directly with with Mr Putin no way
that's going to happen and there's no
way Mr zalinsky has now the option of
dealing with with Mr Trump either
because Mr Trump can't stand him now
look at that the two men who are in a
position to determine the fate of his
nation and his own life he has
completely antagonized
them um so now Ukraine's fate will be
decided without the involvement even
nominal of Mr zilinski he can protest
all he wants but what's going to happen
is is going to
happen uh what happens to Mr zinsky long
term we don't know uh I in in previous
episodes would have said that you know
maybe there's a POS possibility that Mr
zalinski will take his illicit billions
of dollars that he has siphoned off and
he may go and live in California or
something that option is on the table
now the
US no longer will welcome Mr zinski
So eventually when things settle down
and Mr zinski is no longer in power
which is going to happen sooner rather
than later regime change what's going to
happen to Mr zilinski will any EU Nation
give him give him Asylum we'll see about
that uh so yeah Ukraine gets a bad deal
because it's a nation that's helpless
and non Sovereign it's not a Sovereign
Nation so the two sovereign powers with
will decide what happens to Ukraine
Ukraine is going to be
partitioned and after the partitioning
is determined the parameters of the
partitioning and the lines on the map
are drawn there's going to be a regime
change in Kiev let me tell you this
today there's going to be regime change
in Kev and Mr zalinski is in no position
to prevent that from happening and he'll
be very lucky Mr zinski if
um if he gets asylum in some Nation
and can make his way there safely so
yeah that is the deal Ukraine is going
to lose a lot unfortunately because of
the choices made by quizzing like
zilinski okay pray Paul says with Trump
now aligning with Russia in the name of
Peace quotation marks is it genuine or
is this just classic us strategy which
proves Mr Kissinger right that to be an
enemy of the US is dangerous but to be a
friend is
fatal well is Mr Trump aligning with
Russia in the name of Peace no Mr Trump
is trying to fulfill the promise he made
to his voters that he will end the war
and it's
just the way it is that the only way to
end the war is to end the war with the
lines of the map essentially where they
are which means Russia gets what it
wants
if Mr Trump does not give Mr Putin what
Mr Putin has always sought from day one
of the war then the war will continue
and then then Mr Putin may
actually roll over Ukraine and take more
than half of Ukraine or who knows the
whole of it do you want that the Russian
military has grown stronger the past
three years you know historically if you
if you know Russian history they never
start a war well they initially are
caught kind of unprepared even if they
have started the hostilities and the
first few months they don't do really
well but then they slowly start getting
better and better this is what history
tells us and today Russia's military is
a lean mean fighting machine their
entire economy is now a war economy
their production lines are are pushing
out arms ammunition everything they are
in great
shape and there's no European nation
that can withstand the might of the
Russian military right now and I don't
think Mr Putin has any uh any Ambitions
of taking any
Nation outside of Ukraine west west of
Ukraine he I don't think he has any such
uh dreams or Ambitions he's not
harboring in Ambitions so the best way
to have peace today is to let Russia win
this war and achieve their objectives
and in exchange you get guarantees from
Russia that Russia will not not expand
westwards and then you can have some
kind of deal that you will have
peacekeepers in Ukraine in the in the
non-russian part of Ukraine and a
neutral regime which means zinsky goes
and some other safeguards will will be
put in place by nato in the NATO Nations
west of Ukraine that sort of arrangement
will have to be negotiated and agreed
between the US and
Russia um so he Trump is not doing this
in the name of Peace he's not aligning
with Russia he's he is ending the war
which is good for the
world peace is what everyone wants Mr
Modi has been saying this since 2022
this is not a time for war we need peace
so finally we are going to have that so
this is a genuine thing he's doing he's
not doing it because he loves Russia and
loves Putin or is a great fan of Putin
he does respect Putin
obviously a world leader would be stupid
not to respect Putin right um so now
coming to Mr kissen quote the late Mr
Kissinger did say that to be an enemy of
the US is dangerous but to be a friend
is fatal generally when he was referring
to friends he was talking about wasal
you
know uh Saddam Hussein was one of those
wasal one of those
friends mamar Gaddafi the past to some
extent uh Usama bin ladin fought fought
on behalf of the US in Afghanistan we
know what happened to all these
gentlemen uh so zinski is in that
league so your your court is appropriate
it's
apt but it's uh apt for Ukraine and for
zalinski zalinski has been a you could
say on on the receiving end of us
friendship and Ukraine as a nation has
been the past three years on the
receiving end of us friendship and now
there's going to be a price to pay you
going lose your territory about 20%
roughly give or take of Ukrainian
territory and they're going to use
they're going to ukine will lose its
natural mineral
wealth and uh we'll see what else it
loses so yeah it's it's all kind of
fatal for Ukraine and for zalinski who
knows we'll see what happens what Fate
has in store for
zilinski mcloven says what was the point
of public humiliation of zalinski is um
is this the New Politics was Trump
planning to do the same with prime
minister
Modi what was the point of public
humiliation of Mr
zilinski is this New
Politics Trump did not go into the press
conference in the O office with the aim
or objective of humiliating Mr zilinski
if you see if you watch a three minute
clip or a five minute clip you will get
the feeling that zalinski was brought in
there so that he could be humiliated you
will get the sense that he was ambushed
and he had no idea what happened he was
caught unawares but if you take the time
to watch the 50 minute video from
beginning to end you will see there was
it was never the objective you will see
Mr Trump in the beginning says at least
a couple of times at least twice that it
is a great honor to have Mr zilinski
here he's very polite he's very warm
he's very
welcoming it's only about I don't know
40 minutes into the interaction that Zen
you know he pushes too many buttons too
many wrong buttons and then all hell
breaks loose zalinski brought this on
himself zelinsky was looking for a fight
he was like a drunk man in a going to a
bar looking for a fight who who do I
fight I want to fight someone that's the
kind of attitude he has look at his body
language closed off like like a surly
teenager like this disrespectful rude
shrugging his shoulders rolling his eyes
rolling his eyes like that when JD Vans
or Trump are speaking extremely
disrespectful this was not a public
humiliation zalinski asked for it you
don't disrespect the most powerful man
in the world you don't disrespect the
office of the US presidents you don't do
this in the in the old office have some
sense of courtesy have some sense of
Shame you don't disrespect your hosts
it's basic
manners basic manners basic curtsy looks
like he's a he doesn't even have that
zilinski so please don't blame Trump for
what happened to zilinski zilinsky
brought this upon
himself they were supposed to sign that
minerals that mineral wealth deal after
this H so see the problem is when we
watch a three minute or five minute clip
we may not get understand the full
context of what happened okay so I would
recommend please go ahead Whoever has
this impression that zalinski was
humiliated and he was ambushed and so on
I would recommend to all of you who
think that way to watch the entire 50
roughly 50-minute interaction it's
available wherever on social
media then you will see that
zalinski is the person who caused this
it wasn't Trump who did this or or Vans
zalinski went in looking for a fight and
eventually you know
Trump trump uh tried to you know Let it
go so many times
he stayed quiet but eventually it was
too much I think Trump lost it when
zalinsky started accusing J van of of
raising his voice if you're going to
talk with a loud voice it's not going to
make you right you don't insult your
hosts like
that H so please watch the whole thing
then you would understand what really
happened and was Trump planning to do
the same with PM Modi absolutely
not Mighty modok says what's with the
Trump and zilinsky drama after seeing
that the compliment from Trump 2.0 about
Modi being a better and tougher
negotiator seems awesome what's going to
happen to zinsky now have a bad feeling
about his future okay forget about zin's
future let's talk about let's talk about
Trump and Modi Mr Modi was there a
couple I don't know this month I think
yeah last month February um not a long
time ago not not a I think a couple of
weeks ago Mr Modi was there in
Washington DC the same old office and
you can see the the difference in body
language and warmth Etc when Mr Trump
and Mr Modi were in the O office and the
interaction happened there Mr Trump was
so respectful towards Mr Modi and Mr
Modi likewise was similarly respectful
towards Mr Trump you can see you could
see that there is a sense of camarad a
sense of friendship between the two
leaders and you could see that uh
negotiations have happened and there
must have been tough negotiations but
both sides seem to be reasonably happy
and
satisfied neither of the sides you could
see from the body language and
expressions and all neither side felt
like they had been taken advantage of
unduly so it was a very positive media
interaction when Mr Modi was there with
with Mr Trump now I can assure you that
when the cameras are rolling everybody
was on their best behavior you were very
courteous you're very diplomatic and
when you're negotiating behind closed
doors it's a whole different world and
none of those Nic days apply there's
going to be arm twisting there's going
to be bullying all that
and it's possible those things may have
happened during the interaction between
Mr Trump and Mr Modi behind closed
doors right but clearly India did not
come out as a very big loser from that
interaction India will will work on the
tariffs issue we will lower tariffs some
of them some of these tariffs have
already been lowered and all so see when
you go to Washington DC as as a leader
and you meeting with Mr Trump you have
to understand he is more powerful than
you he has way more leverage than
you so you have to do your homework what
does Trump want what does Mr Trump want
from this relationship between if you're
the prime minister of India what does Mr
Trump want from the US India
relationship what does he seek from Mr
Modi during this visit Mr
Trump is a great
negotiator and Mr Trump always wants
wins for the US
so you have to go in there prepared to
give Mr Trump some wins that he can show
to the public US public that see I won
but you have to do it in such a way that
you don't lose as a consequence it has
to be a win-win thing it has to be
balanced so you really need to do your
homework and you to give Mr Trump wins
you have to make him feel happy and then
he's going to help you out as
well he's a reasonably fair man uh
unless you're stupid and you give
everything up you have to be a tough
negotiator but you have to be courteous
you you have to give Mr Trump wins and
so on it's it's not easy diplomacy isn't
easy it's really difficult and only the
tough survive in that so clearly Mr Modi
has done a great job it safeguarding our
national interests when it comes to the
negotiations and diplomacy with the US
with Mr
Trump that cannot be denied so that's
awesome absolutely awesome
so
yeah aren't we lucky we have that we
have Mr
Modi life is Meaningful says Mr Putin
has invited Trump Modi and Mr xiin ping
for the May Victory Parade in Moscow is
there any possibility for a joint
statement of the top four nations in the
world you know I've been saying for such
a long time there are top there are four
nations there are only four nations in
the world that are genuinely Sovereign
which is the US Russia India and China
well there you have it Mr Putin invites
the other three so there you have it he
hasn't invited Mr M of France or any
other Nation only these three Trump Modi
and she which tells you there are only
four genuinely Sovereign nations in the
world um
now uh uh we'll see whether these
invitations will be accepted Mr Trump
has said that he's going to meet with Mr
Putin and resolve the whole matter
um so maybe Mr Trump will go to Moscow
maybe Mr Putin comes to Washington
whichever way it works or maybe a third
location we'll see about that but things
are going back on the right track and
the hostility seems to be ending between
the US and
Russia and now Mr Putin obviously he
wants to uh see he's been isolated
Russia has been isolated for the past
three three plus years so it's it's a
good opportunity for Russia to show the
world that it's back uh things are back
to normal and
the big world leaders can all come
together and meet with him in Moscow for
this historical thing the victory in May
Victory prayed so we'll see will Mr
Trump accept this will Mr Modi accept
this will Mr shei accept it and there's
going to be a lot of considerations in
that but it would be great to see these
four leaders together in
Moscow um right the US China
relationship is a whole different Beast
uh that also we we have to uh you know
uh consider that and lots of
parameters uh and variables in that as
well so we'll see and if let's say Mr
Trump or Mr let's say Mr Trump
hypothetically you know decides not to
come then should Mr Modi go and Mr
should Mr she also go or will it offend
Mr Trump if you know there all kinds of
considerations so I think there's going
to be
consultations between Mr Modi and Mr
Trump and Mr Modi and Mr she Mr Trump
and Mr she and so on so forth it's going
to be complicated but it will be nice to
see all four leaders in Moscow for this
event and if all four are there there
could be some kind of joint statement
definitely and Mr Trump will want I'm
sure at least half of the joint
statement because you know status is Mr
Number One the most powerful man in the
world so yes all that also is taken into
consideration so it'll be great if this
actually happens it'll be great
wonderful
okay drenen Smith says I live in
Australia Australia and I'm worried
about recent change in global politics
Trump is trying to improve and normalize
relations with dictator Putin and it
seems like he also wants to work with
China and he thinks that us is some kind
of a company and he's the CEO of it and
that his company is in a a state of loss
right now you know that China regularly
violates Australian Waters what steps
should Australia take in this rapid
changing of the world
order
right so yeah Putin is a dictator fine
let's
let's do away with the Nic tees and all
that sure he's a dictator so is Mr shei
Mr shei is also dictator right he's kind
of the emperor of China and Mr Putin is
kind of the the tar of Russia yeah um
and Trump thinks that the US is some
kind of a company and he's the CEO of it
well that's typically how uh proactive
president has historic
been
um and if you want to really take away
all the all the niceties then Australia
is like a us-owned
corporation okay you have permanent US
military bases in Australia you always
have US troops on Australian soil and
Australia is essentially a us
protectorate um until the
1940s uh the UK was in charge of
Australia's protection essentially and
then the UK became a second rate world
power because of the events of the 194s
the world war and so on and then the US
assumed the role of the protector and
guardian of Australia now if you look at
the history the US Canada it's the five
five anglosphere nations right so
culturally linguistically ethnically
very similar
Nations um so if you look at the world
from a very realistic hard-nosed
perspective there is one major Empire in
the world which is the US Empire um it's
nothing but a continuation of the
British Empire in 1944 45 the capital of
the Empire moved from London UK to
Washington DC that's all that happened
and it's the same entity that continues
to rule the world and Australia is is a
component of that Australia is like a
us-owned
corporation and uh so the US is in
charge of of Australia security and in
the 40s there was the worry in Australia
that the Japanese would invade and the
US had to step in and ensure this
doesn't happen and eventually we know
the
history and today there is a concern
about China in
Australia so and there's also concerns
in Australia that Australia is deeply
infiltrated by the Chinese you know in
various ways so yeah all these uh issues
are there so first of all let's look at
the world from a very realistic
pragmatic hard-nose perspective Putin is
a dictator she is a dictator the US is
an Empire Trump is the current Emperor
CEO of the US which he see seems to
consider to be company sure and to take
it further Australia is a US possession
a US owned
Corporation the Prime Minister of
Australia is not really a person who's
genuinely in power he does whatever uh
the US wants him to do to he will never
take any action that will be detrimental
to us interests and if he does then he
won't stay in power too long so that's
the situation in the world but you know
what it doesn't matter because the
people are reasonably prosperous you
have reasonable amounts of Freedom
unless there's a lockdown or whatever
but that that's how it goes you know the
Western world is one giant police state
which is the truth ask
any ask any politician from the EU for
example you know off the Record they'll
admit it's the the Western world is a
police state but that's how it is so now
the question is what does Australia do
in this rapidly changing World Order
what steps should Australia take to uh
to safeguard its interests its National
interest what should Australia do so
first of all um Australia
needs Australia needs us
protection and and you need to save got
your very
large uh Coastline and your territorial
Waters the Chinese Navy is a big threat
now right we know that they have the the
largest Navy in terms of numbers in the
world maybe not the most powerful navy
but definitely the largest navy the most
number of Warships in the
world and I'm not sure how many missiles
they can deploy but I'm sure it's a
sizable number of missiles so that's uh
a big area of concern for Australia the
Chinese have multiple aircraft carriers
now so the U so Australia needs us
protection you need American military
bases on your territory you need uh
interoperability with the US military
which you have yes uh maybe another
thing you can do is have US nuclear
weapons on your soil I mean in the in
the 20th century you did allow the
Americans to test at least one nuclear
weapon on Australian soil didn't you uh
so you need that
and um yeah so essentially you need us
help to ward off the China
threat and uh the Chinese obviously uh
are
currently facing lots of issues with the
US uh Trump started the trade war in 20
during his first presidency and there
was a historical reversal of US policy
towards China and now the two nations
are well adversaries in a variety of in
all domains essentially in technology in
the military domain in the naval domain
in space in uh diplomacy in everything
in in economics in trade everything
their adversaries so um you need the US
on your side the Chinese you know nobody
talks about China's rise anymore China's
peaceful rise which was not very
peaceful it was kind of scary you know
very threatening but now they've toned
it down but the threat remains from your
perspective so you need the US on your
side democracy and all it's
okay and you need to bolster your
military as well so you need your own
submarines you have this Au us deal
you're going to have a bunch
of uh nuclear
submarines which will technically be
yours but it it will be those will be
operated by
Americans from Australian ports well
whatever it's okay as long as it keeps
you safe so that's what you need to do
essentially to to make a long story
short you need to put all your eggs in
the US basket and you're part of the
Quad as well which means you're going to
have
interoperability with the New Zealand
not New Zealand with with the Americans
the Japanese and to some extent us the
Indians um and obviously the quad is
focused around China the Chinese threat
so yeah you need to participate in all
of this and be friends with all
like-minded nations All Nations that are
scared of China including us China is
scary believe it believe me so that's
what you need to
do right next
question why will the US give $400
million to Pakistan Trump announced har
War says Trump announced $400 million
Aid or whatever to Pakistan what's your
take on this it reminds me of your
saying on previous live session
nothing changes for India everything is
in its place yeah
so there have been people you
know there's been this this sentiment in
India that when Trump comes to power
Everything Will Change and uh you know
everything will be better for India
Trump will
uh uh what bring shik Hina back to Power
in East Pakistan and so on things don't
change that way if the US has leverage
over you they will never give it
up so on the 26th of February this year
today is the 1st of March I'm talking
about 26th of February which is
Wednesday today is Saturday this
Wednesday just three days ago on the
26th of February which is the
anniversary of the balakot air strike on
that day Trump announced that he's
releasing 400 million or whatever
dollars as Aid to Pakistan to to
refurbish or or or or maintain for
maintenance of their F-16 fighter
planes but strictly for the purpose of
countering terrorism what what how do
you use fighter planes to counter
terrorism it's like using a machine gun
to to shoot mosquitoes yeah using
f-16s to Target terrorists is like using
a machine gun to Target
mosquitoes so Trump is releasing a
certain amount of money to Pakistan so
that they can um do maintenance or
whatever on their F-16 Fleet so
obviously the pakistanis why do they
have f-16s to Target India we all know
that right it's not for terrorists it's
for India uh so why is Trump doing this
it's obviously he's placing pressure on
India is reminding India that I have all
kinds of Leverage over you I can this is
just a reminder $400 million is not a
really big big amount of money actually
but he's reminding India I have so many
ways of pressurizing you on applying
pressure and leverage over you you
better do what I want it's a friendly
reminder essentially
uh so they are not so Trump is not going
to bring shik hen back to Power he not
goingon to undo the regime change that
happen in East Pakistan Bangladesh and
he will prop up the West Pakistan wasal
regime as well there are some people on
Twitter who claim that Pakistan is a
Sovereign Nation and not a wasal of the
US I mean what delusional world are you
living in the US affected a regime
change in Pakistan in the year
2022 they ousted Imran Khan who was Pro
China and they brought in whoever is the
current prime minister of Pakistan and
now Pakistan is a full fledged US vasal
state and the US will not give up that
Leverage
otherwise Pakistan will go back to
another Daddy see the Pakistani military
always needs a big daddy somewhere it's
either China or or the US historically
it's been the us then China for a decade
or so after the US lost interest and now
it's the US again so the US owns
Pakistan and Pakistan's government and
Military why will they give up that
leverage uh so it's not a big setback
it's not a big issue for India us ties
but yeah it's a it's another reminder
from Trump and from the the US that you
guys stay in your L Lane don't get off
reservation remember who you are
remember we have all kinds of Leverage
over you so
behave we have these issues and you need
to give us what we want lower the
tariffs do this do that
whatever so that's how the game is
played it's a game of
Leverage prakar Gupta says please
explain the whole recent situation
developing between the US Russia Ukraine
regarding peace deals why has the US
suddenly started supporting its biggest
rival Russia is Trump going to end his
rivalry and take us Russia relationship
to the pre-cold War era he's also
bashing zinsky for the for starting the
war and forcing him to sign the minerals
deal what's your take on this entire
issue if the US and Russia become allies
now how will it affect global
geopolitics and especially bhat to
recap everything that's happening Trump
wants to end this Wast ful War he
understands and he realizes that Russia
has the upper hand and there's nothing
the Americans or NATO or Europe can do
to undo the gains Russia and Putin have
acquired in Ukraine there's no way the
Russians will tolerate Ukraine becoming
a member of NATO and there's no way they
will tolerate any crossing of the red
lines so this war the Americans thus far
have already spent about 3400 billion
dollars tremendous amount of money
they're leaking money they're bleeding
money it's enough this is a pointless
War um it's it's damaging the US economy
draining US money so Trump wants to end
this uh so that's why the war is now in
the end game phase Trump and Putin and
their minions will get together uh you
know hammer out the parameters of the
deal and then there's going to be
ceasefire which will involve Putin
getting everything he wants which is a
victory which is a victory for Russia in
the war he will keep the territory he
has gained he will ensure that Ukraine
remains neutral Ukraine never becomes a
member of NATO he will ensure that there
there's denazification and
demilitarization of Ukraine which means
that there's going to be peacekeepers of
some kind in Ukraine but the Ukraine
military has to put down its
weapons he has already deated the aov
regiment which means to a large extent
Ukraine is deified at least he can tell
his people that it's done and he's going
to ensure that zinski is
oued this regime change so Putin gets
everything he wants everything he wanted
on February 22 2022 he will get all of
that and it's not a big loss for the US
it's actually good that the war
ends um so Trump is not supporting his
biggest rival the US is not supporting
his biggest rival they're just ending
the war
and you to understand another thing
there's a China Factor here see the war
has pushed Russia very
close into a very close Embrace with
China and from the US perspective China
is a very big uh rival and a very big
concern for the US especially China's
technological growth technological uh
advances uh in various Fields including
AI including all kinds of other stuff so
and and China is the second largest
economy in the world they have issues
and so on but China is a very big
concern to the US and China's expanding
Naval strength military strength all of
this is a big concern for the US so the
US would like to kind of take Russia out
of this tight Embrace with China how do
you do that you and first of all you end
the war give Putin what he wants
secondly you ease the sanctions you uh
so if you ease the sanctions then you
can the S sanctions had decoupled Russia
the Russian economy from the Western
econ e omy so now you open up those ties
again and of course you have to remember
that everything was not shut down there
is this if you go to any airp major
airport and you will see that there is
an airline called Aero flot Russian
airline their planes are mostly Western
planes boeings and air buses and so
those pairs and supplies the supply of
that still continued during the war so
not everything was not shut down but
yeah Russia's banking system economic
system was decoupled from Swift and so
on so that may happen again so if Russia
gets access to the Western economy again
then their tremendous dependence on
China will not be such a big factor
anymore and Russia can be able will be
able to kind of decouple to some extent
from China of course they will not
completely give that up Russia also
understands that China is a
valuable partner to have so is India so
what the US wants to do is they want to
take Russia out of its tight Embrace
from China they want to make China feel
more isolated so that they can
eventually the big big agenda is to is
to reign in China to clamp down on China
and ensure that China doesn't become a
great great power or potential super
power in the future that's the big
objective Trump's big game is China it's
not Russia Russia can be dealt with by
ending the war which will happen soon so
that's actually what's happening zinsky
is they're going to get rid of him at
the
earliest um so Trump is ending the
hostility Etc with Russia he's going to
make life easier for Russia he will
probably ease a lot of sanctions uh
bring Russia back into the fold of the
global
economy and then he's going to focus on
China and in that he's going to need
India as well uh so the US and Russia
not become allies all that happens is
that the hostility ends and they are no
no longer enemies it doesn't become it
doesn't mean that they become allies
just because they have ended the war
they're ending the war and they are no
longer enemies it doesn't be mean that
they have become allies please
understand the
distinction um so yeah once this happens
once the war ends once do a seize fire
and Putin gets what he wants and zinski
is out and so on so forth all of that
stuff then the war has ended they are no
longer enemies then what happens then is
Trump and the US start focusing on
China then there's going to be
consequences coming out of that all
kinds of first order second order
consequences and and it's going to
involve India to some extent maybe to a
large extent because the Americans will
want India on their side they're going
to tell us you're either with us or
against us then we have to pick a side
but at least we don't have to go against
Russia right the past let's say a year
or so there have been
attempts uh serious concerted attempts
by India and China to to bring down the
the hostility that started with the
Galvan Clash 2020 and that succeeded to
a significant extent of course we
haven't uh we we haven't uh demarcated
the boundary the India Tibet border
which is the main bard of contention but
the temperature and hostility has come
down the two armies are no longer St
staring eyeball to eyeball to a large
extent and patrolling is now happening
in a peaceful Manner and so on
so
there is this area this this um this
climate of improving relations between
India and China and uh the US may not
like that very much so that is where it
could affect India that's where it could
affect Barat it could U Place us in a
position where we have to make a choice
either we want friendly relations with
China or we to end all that and become
kind of a Us tool in its toolkit of uh
containing and insing China so that is
what could be coming up for us in the
next 3 four
years okay NASA machino mov whatever
says why has the EU president Ursula on
their Lane why she visited India what
are her are her intentions how will
India benefit from the EU what are
India's opportunities Visa the EU well
European working travel visas be become
easy for Indian citizens what are My
Views okay so the visit has just
happened and instead of me trying and
remember what all happened let me put
out this this report on the screen and
we will read it together it's by this
reporter journalist called sidan SI and
he has listed all the activities this is
this this tweet is from yesterday so
it's it's very recent uh so let's see uh
what all
what all has happened so let's
read so it's very rare for EU Comm EU
president along with 22 Commissioners
cabinet ministers to travel bilaterally
to any country in such a format this
visit shows how Brussels is Keen to firm
up ties with India so let's find out
what are the outcomes of this visit
right let's let's find out the
outcomes uh India and EU Free Trade
Agreement both leaders gave a big
political push for the conclusion of the
Free Trade Agreement which has
been apparently languishing for decades
so we are hoping to conclude the Free
Trade Agreement by the end of this year
uh this comes As Trump tariff worries
remain a key concern for India as well
as for the EU and the EU wants reduction
of tariffs especially cars and
Vines not only FDA but focus on
conclusion of agreement on investment
protection and geographical indications
by year end discussed clear political
pushed by top Indian and European
leaders for the Free Trade Agreement
10th round of FDA talks will take place
in Brussels next
month diversification and drisking call
for strengthening supply chain
resilience basically reducing
dependencies on China which everybody
will welcome trusted and secure value
chain is our common common priority
which is what PR PM Modi has said and
the EU commission president said we need
to build robust and diverse Supply
chains there is talk of climate uh joint
research on EV batteries Marine Plastics
green hydrogen offshore wind business
Summit has been planned EU imposed
tariffs on EV batteries from China which
is a big Global shair share to counter
go government unfair
subsidies strategic technology deepening
cooperation in semiconductors AI
6G uh and so
on
um TTC is a key pillar of India EU ties
uh launch in 23 and so on there's a
joint statement green connect green
energy clean energy green
hydrogen um some symbolic things like
going uh traveling in a hydrogen powered
bus and connectivity the imech is
interesting India middle east Europe
economic Corridor ime Corridor was
discussed at Great length both leaders
mentioned it so it's expected to make uh
The Rail Link is expected to make trade
between India and Europe 40% faster okay
let's see what happens with that then
there's defense security and defense
partnership the EU is looking for such a
partnership with India on the lines of
what the EU has with Japan South Korea
um India has shown interest in joining
eu's permanent structured cooperation
Pesco more Maritime
exercises new space dialogue security of
information agreement counterterrorism
operations crossb terrorism about
Pakistan cyber security Marine security
and so many other issues so many other
issues looks like a very substantial
thing I will not go through the whole
thing but you get the point it's been a
very
substantial um visit and lots of
substantial things were discussed and
let's see how uh what the outcomes and
actual
tangible measurables are of this but
looks like a good visit uh looks like a
productive visit so the intentions are
that both India and the you as an
economic block need to work together in
a mutually beneficial way win-win way we
can do all this stuff together and
there's lots of opportunities for here
for us over here I did not see anything
about visas travel visas it would be
good for indianan Citizens if it becomes
easier to travel to the EU right now
there's a very long tedious cumbersome
Visa process you to give I hear a
bajillion documents to get a EU Visa
maybe we can talk about that I mean our
leaders can talk with the EU leaders
about that and make the process easier
it would be
nice um but I do not see anything about
about visas in what I just read so we'll
see we'll see how it goes but overall it
seems to be good and uh something that
we should all
welcome okay life is Meaningful says
what are the biggest delusions that
people of India live in according to me
Indians have uh India biggest delusions
that's that's an interesting
question um there's a lot of delusions
that Indians labor under no question
about it what are the biggest
ones you know our national slogan is
sat truth always prevails that's a
delusion
truth prevails only if it is backed up
by strength do you understand that and
if you look at Indian politicians and
everything do you see that
following this adage of sat
J I'm not talking about all politicians
there are some good politicians no doubt
in India some really great politicians
but if you look at the majority of
politicians you may see that sat doesn't
apply there right so the big one big
delusion is sat that we Indians believe
that truth always prevails no sir no
ma'am strength prevails not truth so for
truth to Prevail it needs to be backed
up by strength hard
power okay that's one delusion another
delusion
is uh the lots of Indians believe that
nonviolence won us our
independence right we became independent
we won our our independence through
nonviolence that's a delusion we are
still colonized because we got this
transfer of power through
nonviolence which ensured that the
British were able to handpick their
successors who would who they would hand
power to in India and that's why India
is still deeply deeply colonized and we
have so many issues had India won its
independence through
violence then we would have a completely
different system
today so nonviolence did not win us
independence it what it ensured is that
we remain colonized and nothing changes
the entire system of governance and the
entire governance Machinery the entire
education system everything is still
briti still Colonial nonviolence did not
win us any
Independence another thing people ask is
uh when when faced with some some
geopolitical choice they ask what would
Gandhi do what would Mr mandas karaman
Gandhi do what we should actually ask
ourselves is what would Khali
do not what Mr what would Mr Gandhi do
what would k do goddess KH you know all
your gods they wield
weapons deadly weapons bloody
weapons right so don't ask yourself what
would Mr Gandhi do ask yourself what
would Khali do or your favorite god or
goddess do understand that we are
sovereign as a nation not because we are
nonviolent but because we have nuclear
weapons and the means to deliver those
nuclear weapons that's why we are
sovereign so please enough of this Del I
usion of
nonviolence and there
Isa
kakam kakam the world is one
family if you read the jataka Tales
jataka tales you will see that the story
that has this slogan veva kutumbakam
that story is a cautionary
tale and you the moral of that story is
that the world is not one family it's
it's a cautionary tale vuda kutumbakam
so stop believing the world is one
family the world is not one
family then there is this uh
delusion uh PE Indians have about
India's soft power Indians are obsessed
with soft power that's a delusion soft
power doesn't exist unless you have hard
power soft power is you will be
respected as a nation only if you have
hard power and then people will value
your soft power but if you are a poor
miserable third world country incapable
of Defending itself no matter how great
your culture is nobody will value You So
Soft power only
exists if you have sufficient hard power
that's another delusions Indians labor
under then there is this delusion in
India
that that unilateral concessions will
will wi you friends what are examples of
UN atal
concessions the partition of India we
gave away our ancestor
lands you know that was a unilateral
concession what would we what did we get
in exchange we
got two enemies on on our East and West
flanks
right and the Kashmir issue and all that
unilaterally giving away your territory
what did it bring us any peace it did
not bring us any peace another example
of a unilateral concession is giving up
Tibet to China Tibet was historically
our protectorate for the best part of
two 2,000
years it was part of the indosphere of
our extended cultural zone of influence
and Mr Neu gave it away handed away
handed it away to to China on a platter
in the 1950s unilateral concession here
take it now we can be friends you sure
yeah are we friends
today there are so many other things
uh in the
2000s unfortunate but true prime
minister vajpai unilaterally recognized
Tibet as part of China until then India
had not recognized Tibet as a part of
China Mr vaj
unilaterally did this you know it was a
unilateral concession okay we recognize
Tibet as a part of China now let's be
friends so he must have thought that
we'll immediately become friends but
what immediately happened is that China
then laid claim on Aral Pradesh which it
had not done until then so these
unilateral concessions if it's a big
delusion to believe that it it works it
never works another delusion we have is
that we are almost a
superpower lots of Indians believe that
we are about to be a superpower in 5 10
years are you people kidding me
we are a poor third world nation with a
tremendous amount of
problems so many problems corruption
this that what
not yeah
superpower even China is not a
superpower there's only one superpower
the US you think you can be anywhere
close to that in in the near future
you're going to have to work really
really hard to even be on the same level
as Russia or China really hard
it it will take at least until
2050 what superpower I'm not making fun
of people's aspirations that India
should be a superpower I would love for
India to be a superpower but to imagine
that we are on the brink of being a
superpower is a joke it's a delusion we
are nowhere close to being a superpower
we are not even close to anywhere being
as strong as the top three nations the
US Russia and
China we are
we we are not even in the in the same
league as China we may be civilization
much older than that it counts for
nothing the only thing that really
counts in geopolitics is hard power and
we are nowhere close to even China
forget about Russia or the US superpower
no
superpower um then this other myth of
this other delusion that India is a
visha guru India is a visha student
right now we have the world one of the
world's worst education systems and you
think we'll be visha
Guru I mean you have to reform the
education system to be a visha guru we
have to produce the bulk of the world's
wisdom and
knowledge right now if you if you want
knowledge if you want an education a
good education an Indian kid an Indian
student will go to the US to get a good
education and there he or she will have
an Indian Professor that's how bad India
is so we are no Vish we are no we are
not even a visha student right now we
are a visha
Ki sad to say I mean these are
delusions then there is this myth that
English
education makes you intelligent another
stupid myth it makes you
dumb the English language is is is not
some superpower language that that makes
you automatically intelligent if you can
speak in a certain
accent it's just a language it's just
it's just a tool so so there this
another delusion Indians have that if
you can speak English you are
automatically Superior to everybody else
and you are automatically more
intelligent than everybody else what an
idiotic delusion then there's this
delusion that certain countries are are
our brother countries I will not name
them because it will upset people but
Indians have this great love
for one or two countries and lots of
Indians will put those countries flags
in their social media picture profile
social media profiles
and the citizens of those countries will
be laughing privately at us and mocking
us for being so stupid and
delusional um another delusion is that
lots of Indians have is that it is
glorious to be poor poverty is glorious
suffering is glorious and being rich is
bad it's
decadent we were the nation with the
world's highest GDP
for the longest
time we were genuinely rich and
prosperous for the longest period of
History so why are we suddenly
glorifying poverty now poverty and and
misery and all that lots of Indians lots
of
Indians are jealous of people who have
wealth and you automatically assume that
they must have done something crooked to
get that wealth right it's because of
the system that India has that you
cannot succeed un unless you are corrupt
well things are changing now so we
should stop
stigmatizing uh wealth it is glorious to
be wealthy like then shoing said and I
would like everybody in this country to
be
wealthy so that's a delusion Indians
have that you know wealth is is bad weal
being wealthy is bad and wealth corrupts
you somehow no it doesn't it doesn't
corrupt you it only empowers you to do
things according to your nature that's
what wealth does another delusion
Indians
have so I went to a podcast as as a as a
guest to a podcast and the
host was telling me I I'm not blame him
for this but it seems lots of Indians
believe that if somebody has been living
in India for a number of years they
become naturalized citizens of
India or if your your parents or
ancestors were illegal immigrants then
if you are born in India then you are
naturalized
Indians that is so wrong
that is so wrong illegal immigrants and
their descendants can never be
naturalized to of India if you are an
illegal immigrant you are a
criminal because
infiltrating into India immigrating into
India illegally is obviously a
crime and India does not have the
concept of usus sui which is citizenship
by birth which the Americans
have if a child is born on Indian soil
it does not make the child an Indian
citizen so we have to understand this
that the descendants of illegal
immigrants are not
Indians and illegal immigrants if they
stay 20 30 years they don't become
Indians by naturalization absolutely not
if you yeah we have a process of
naturalization which only applies to
Legal immigrants not to illegal
immigrants so there's so many delusions
I could go on I could do a two-hour live
stream about the delusions the Indians
suffer from but I think uh I've covered
a few I've covered a few please think
about these things lots of Indians are
delusional like this it's not your fault
the education system doesn't teach you
what you're supposed to be taught so
that's why you have these delusions it's
not your fault it is what it
is the priest of Varanasi says Elon Musk
recently tweeted about the closing of
the first transgender clinic in India
due to the US Aid freeze what are my
thoughts about this well good
that's all kinds of Nefarious nonsense
these USA folks were doing in India and
because of the uh the freeze on usaid
all of that will now be shut down and
you can see you know transgender clinic
so converting regular people into
transgender people that's what they were
trying to do that was their ideology
right the voke ideology that everybody
should be mutilated and their their
their
their various organs should be
transformed into or organs of the of the
other gender or you can have multiple
genders I don't know what the hell it is
I have zero interest in that but that's
the kind of ideology and worldview they
were trying to engineer in India now
please understand that now that Trump is
in power that woke ideology is no longer
in
currency um the various American
corporations are no longer pushing the
ideology the woke ideology but do
understand that just because us Aid is
now defunct more or less it doesn't mean
that American interference in India will
end there are so many other means and
mechanisms through which they can funnel
money into
India there there are so many
organizations uh there's Oxfam which is
the U UK based organization there's the
National Endowment for democracy there
is the Gates Foundation the open
societies thing um the Rockefeller
Foundation there are so many NOS there
are so many institutes there are there
are so many
uh so many academics that they fund
there are so many media houses that they
Fund in so many different ways just
because us Aid is shut down or defunct
doesn't mean that the interference will
end yeah the voke nonsense will no
longer be funded but other stuff will
most likely continue to be funded please
don't suffer under you know labor under
the delusion that all of that is now
over it's not over by any
means the missionary conversion will
continue they will continue be to be
funded by from by outside money billions
of dollars every year that's going to
continue that's not ended there's much
more that will continue so yeah please
have a
realistic uh perspective on this
matter
um yeah this is a question uh yeah okay
vickram geopolitical mlav sonat vicam
how do you look at Trump's recent move
of introducing a gold card for5 million
us I don't think it'll have much effect
on India as not many would spend 45 CR
rupees for US citizenship many European
nations also have such Visa policies
which are a lot cheaper Trump is giving
a US is giving a trump gold card where
you can get a US green card for $5
million do you think it's a good move
how will this affect India will this
significantly escalate the money drain
from India as our millionaires been like
the drill what's my opinion on this uh
to attract foreigners to invest in the
US and create jobs and become citizens
in the future can this move really help
the US economy or will it be a ticket
for billionaires and millionaires to
secure a Haven in the US first of all
this golden ticket or whatever it's
called you know Visa by investment no
green card by investment that scheme
already existed it used to cost just a
million just $1 million but now it's
going to cost $5 million so it was
already already there so whoever wanted
to purchase a US Visa all they had to do
was spend $1 million you had to invest
that in a US company or or some business
or start a business and employ X number
of people certain number of people and
then you get get a green card in a in a
short period of time a reasonably short
period of time so that was already there
now it's more expensive five times as
expensive so earlier it was $1 million
which is what 8 point something CR rupes
right now it is about 45 CR rupees much
more expensive but now it's a
golden uh golden green card not a green
card it's a golden card so you have many
more apparently privileges apparently
which I'm not sure what they are I
haven't looked into it but yeah uh how
will this affect India first of all it's
a good great step for the US they're
monetizing the fact that they are the
most popular popular destination
worldwide for people who want to
immigrate to to a to a first world
country
and U you know they could cancel pay off
their entire national debt through the
money they receive through this you only
need a few million people to to buy this
golden card for that to happen so it's
great for the US economy how will it
affect India and I think it'll affect
India a lot I'm sure there are lots of
people in India who can afford that $5
million 45 crores but if somebody
has only let's say 50 it's not only it's
tremendous amount of money let's say you
have 50 CR in your account all your
assets combined 50 crores would you be
willing to spend 45 cres out of course
out of that to get yourself a green a
golden card I think you may not so it
will be uh it will attract only the
super rich Indians the top
0.01% perhaps and it's not going to be a
big dent on the Indian economy but if
you have that sort of wealth flying
lying around maybe you can do it and get
yourself a nice us golden card but like
someone pointed like
uh like like like like who who pointed
like vickram geopolitical pointed out
many European nations and other nations
have such Visa policies I think uh St
kits and Nevis has a nice passport
scheme you essentially get to buy a
passport if you invest I don't know what
whatever amount of money uh various EU
Nations have these golden Visa schemes
uh permanent residency I think you can
even buy a passport in some country Ines
by investing a certain amount of money I
think this Cyprus is a good example I
believe and I believe Portugal in case
some of you have are interested Portugal
has a great great scheme I hear and so
on so it's not only the US that has
these schemes many countries have this
but this is for the super wealthy people
okay someone who has $5 million in lose
change lying around in a pocket or in a
drawer somewhere if you are one of those
people that it's it's a good option for
you uh but it's it's a great way of
thinking you
know it's a the US is a nation that's so
attractive to lots of people most
powerful country wealthiest country
great living standards most prestigious
passport to have so yeah you you
leverage that and put a price tag on
that and you obviously will wet people
whoever
applies so I think it's great but um I'm
not sure how much of an impact is going
to have on the Indian economy it's
possible many people may sell off the
real estate to to raise some extra money
and uh so real estate prices may be
affected perhaps as a consequence of
this but we'll see I don't think it's
going to have too big of an impact on
the Indian
economy
okay Joy deut says the Silicon Valley AI
artificial intelligence folks say that
AGI artificial general intelligence will
be achieved within one or years do you
think the US military has already
developed AGI
internally and is advancing
towards artificial super intelligence
how might how might this impact the US's
role as a global superpower could it
make them
unbeatable so first of all let me Define
these two terms AGI ASI AGI is
artificial general intelligence which
means an artificial intelligence system
AI system that has roughly about 130
human equivalent IQ 130 IQ Q for humans
is supposed to be reasonably intelligent
150 is 150 plus is genius level I
believe and 110 120 plus is is
reasonable intelligent so 130 is a good
amount of intelligence I think top 10%
or something IQ so an AI system with a
human equivalent 130 IQ is what they
call AGI I can I don't entirely agree
with
that if you have human level
intelligence you should also have the
ability to say no but AI don't have the
ability to say no to any task that's
given to them so that's where there's a
difference but okay 130 uh human IQ
that's an AGI system artificial general
intelligence then what's ASI artificial
super intelligence so an ASI system is a
system that AGI will create iteratively
and an ASI system artificial super
intelligence will have an IQ of about
300 or 500 which is super human no human
can have 300 IQ or 500 IQ but this
system will have that so it will it's
going to give you technological
breakthroughs that are in the realm of
science fiction or even
magic okay so that's the deal so that's
why there's this big artificial
intelligence race that's going on and
right now it is said that we may have
AGI in maybe one or two
years uh so we have a number of U EI
systems that are available to the
general public that is open AI GPT
series GPT chart GPT thing and u there
is uh
clothe there is the Chinese deep seek R1
and there is um number of other systems
okay and all of these are reasonably
intelligent I think I believe the latest
Cloe version is super super at at coding
and so on and it is being said that uh
an AGI system may be available in a year
or two what I believe is that behind
closed doors they have already achieved
AGI they may be on the brink of ASI I am
certain about that see what they are
showing to the world is just a fraction
of their actual capabilities that's
always how the world works so I am 100%
certain that AGI has already been
achieved 130 human IQ level uh
artificial intelligence behind closed
doors you may even have be at 250 or 300
uh IQ level you
know so yeah I am pretty sure they
already have way more powerful AI
systems than what we can see in the
public uh
domain uh and that would make the US
unbeatable it would transform them from
a super power into a hyper power and all
these little petty geopolitical issues
will become completely irrelevant that's
how powerful they'll become so what that
does is that it gives them te
technological breakthroughs that nobody
can beat that's technology is always
see at any given point in history at any
given time the greatest power was always
the most advanced technological power
always um even if you look at the Mongol
Empire they had technology they took
whatever technology they could acquire
from wherever they could they didn't
care who who was the source and they
synthesized it into the biggest baddest
meanest leanest deadliest fighting
machine
ever uh so
yeah so this could give them
you know it could transform them from a
super power into a hyper power um yeah
it could make them unbeatable and I'm
pretty sure that they are almost there
more or less more or
less okay uh let's take some more
questions and then if this time I'll
take questions from uh the live chat as
well a
few um recently they are saying that
there's an asteroid 2024 y4 which will
impact the Earth in
2032 and Mumbai is in the range of
possible of the impact possibly in the
in the zone where the asteroid could
potentially impact the Earth what are My
Views about this so yeah there's an
asteroid which apparently
could it's it's its orbit could
intersect with the Earth's orbit in
2032 right now they're saying there's
about
3% roughly probability of this
happening okay the probability is
roughly around 3% right now so in the
future as we can as we study the
asteroid better and we get a better
understanding of its trajectory if its
orbit around the Sun the probability of
impact will change it will either go
towards zero 0% probability or it will
go towards
100% in the unfortunate even eventuality
that the probability of impact with
Earth becomes
100% then there is a certain area of the
Earth a certain Zone where the impact
will happen I hope it never happens but
let's consider the
possibility and that zone of that Impact
Zone it goes across India and Mumbai
seems to
be part of
it so if we are unfortunate the asteroid
may impact India and perhaps Mumbai if
that happens it's end end of the story
for Mumbai if it impacts some other part
of India maybe in a forest or the hill
range or mountain range or whatever it's
not going to cause too much damage um I
haven't yet seen how large the asteroid
is depending on the mass of the asteroid
you can uh
estimate estimate its its
um U the amount of energy such an impact
would give out in terms of kilotons of
TNT which is typically how you calculate
the The Fallout of a nuclear weapon um
so what should we do I think India I I'm
surprised India has has not taken any
action
see it's possible to divert an
asteroid if if if there's an asteroid
that is going to hit the earth in a
certain amount of
time if you have sufficient time you can
divert the trajectory of the asteroid
and ensure that it does not hit the
earth there are multiple ways of doing
it Hollywood will say that you should
nuke the asteroid which is not a good
idea nuking an asteroid is not a good
idea it's not going work what a nuclear
explosion on an asteroid does it
pulverizes the asteroid it breaks it up
into hundreds of thousands maybe
millions of pieces and they are flung
far away but eventually because of the
center of mass gravity they will all
slowly slowly slowly slowly over months
and years come back together and then
the Earth will be hit by not one
asteroid but a billion pieces million
pieces of asteroid and that may not be
very nice uh generally it doesn't work
well you know so have thrown that what
you a better way of doing it of
diverting asteroid is by using a gravity
tractor you send a spacecraft to Shadow
the asteroid and through the gravity of
the space you slowly slowly tug the
asteroid in a different direction slow
gradually but if you have enough time
you can you can change the asid's
trajectory sufficiently so that it will
miss uh it will miss the impact with the
Earth so what India should do is set up
a space
force India should start studying that
story itself and in the eventuality that
it's going to be in a position to impact
the Earth India should you know set up a
space mission to send a gravity tractor
to the asteroid to divert its trajectory
maybe work with China work with the US
work with the Russians whoever the
Chinese have immediately set up space
force to study this India is still
sleeping we have is we have so many
scientific Personnel we are doing
nothing very very passive approach by
India it's a great opportunity for India
to show its prowess to the world and
ensure that India doesn't get nuked by
an asteroid so I would
urge the government of India to wake the
hell
up and uh please take action on this set
up a space task force a task force to
Monitor and um do whatever is required
when it comes to this asteroid in case
we find that it's going to hit the earth
we should be ready with a
plan and with with the means to divert
that story and ensure it doesn't hit the
earth we need to do
that if you agree with me let me know in
the
comments
um Atul Mishra says you have no idea sir
how huge fan I am watching your videos
from the start thank you so much I
really appreciate that genuinely very
much
so um the question is uh what is the
current state of status of bat's
sovereignty and what are what are the
chances what are the challenges it is
facing adding to that what is the most
important part what key points should
India under Modi G and hopefully whoever
else in the future Yogi G perhaps what
should we what key points should India
focus on in order to strengthen its
sovereignty uh see I am very clear about
this I've said this in the past many
times that there are only four genuinely
Sovereign nations in the world US the US
Russia China and India India sovereignty
is you could say it's slightly iffy
because we some of our territories in
Pakistani hands and there is the issue
of Manipur which kind of encroaches on
our sovereignty if you have a few lack
illegal Invaders immigrants squatting on
Indian Territory but if you disregard
all that we are still a fully Sovereign
Nation and we'll we'll hopefully resolve
the the issue in
a certain time frame um so what are the
things India should do to strengthen its
sovereignty right that's the question
you asking first of all our borders need
to be fenced okay first of all all the
borders need to be fenced and wherever
you're not fencing fencing the borders
you need to have sufficient armed
Personnel who are not corrupt at the
border so that they will not take 2,000
Rupees to bring illegal infiltrators in
which allegedly has been happening in
very large numbers in the past
allegedly all right so that's what needs
to happen get rid of the corruption in
the paramilitary forces that are in
charge get rid of the alleged
corruption in the paramilitary forces
that are in charge of safeguarding our
borders
secondly um we need to
uh we need to ensure that the borders
are fenced thirdly get rid of all the
illegal immigrants tremendous number of
illegal Bangladeshi ringas and cookies
in India we need to deport them all
every single illegal infil should be
deported no matter what the ethnicity
that's number three okay and then once
these Solutions these problems are
solved we need to end corruption in the
country the whole country runs on
corruption allegedly I think we all know
that it's the biggest Open Secret in
India and then what India needs to do to
to genuinely Safeguard its sovereignty
is to to strengthen its military and
become technologically independent we
cannot have foreign aircraft in India
why does Trump why does Donald Trump
respect Emmanuel maon but not other
European leaders it's because maon
France makes all of its own aircrafts
its own submarines and its own aircraft
carriers all the fighter planes are
French all the submarines are made by
France the engines are French jet
engines everything is French that's why
France is a quasi Sovereign Nation
despite being a member of the EU and a
member of NATO
India needs to be in that
position so how do we develop this jet
engine nobody is going to give us this
technology the solution is to develop
technologies that will help us develop
jet engines what's the technology it's
AI Mr Ashwini ver of the minister of it
has said that by the end of this year
India will have its own large language
model EI llm right my question is do
they know what they will do with this
llm or are we just making it because
everybody has it and we should also have
the prestige of having our own llm it's
not enough to just have your
llm that llm is a tool that you have to
use to solve problems to make us more
powerful and more
Sovereign so once you have an AGI system
with 130 human IQ or maybe a more
powerful system with 200 human IQ level
then you can solve the intractable
problem of the jet engine whatever is
not working fix it how to develop a
single Crystal nickel blade for the jet
engine all those problems can be solved
with a with AI so we need to really
focus on these things our technological
sovereignty and solving these little
problems big problems actually that have
been plaguing us for so long that's what
we need to do there's so much more we
can do but I think uh I've laid out a
number of things that India should
really do as soon as possible and that
will safeguard our sovereignty and make
us more sovereign
and it will bullet proof our sovereignty
and of course space exploration we can't
be left behind in the Space
Race which we kind of are right now yeah
okay let's take
um couple more questions before I take
live chat
questions okay oh big question o just
says today I attended an event in my
college Vite vnit a conference on Indian
knowledge systems God wish you were
there too okay thank you the chief guest
was the now Vice Chancellor of the Jalal
n University she in her speech
reiterated the same things that I say
about left historians preservation
perversion of our history aian Invasion
Theory myth Women rights and Hindu
culture and so on it seemed to me that
they watched all your videos okay good
to know the question is if such a person
in power there were many people quite
reputed people with the same views if
such a person cannot destroy the leftist
ecosystem even with the present
government what would it take for us to
win it baffles me good question you know
the ageold
problem that sort of thing
right everybody has to every time
there's a transition of power the new
incoming Administration faces these
problems and now the Modi government has
been power for 11 years they're still
facing the problem and it's not the
fault of the Modi government please
understand this it's like this see right
now Trump has come to power
and he wanted the the Epstein files to
be released to the public but the FBI is
not cooperating they're not releasing
all the documents they're hiding stuff
they're suppressing information they are
not releasing it to the government of
the US the
FBI and the head of the FBI the director
is Kash Patel kha Patel a longtime Trump
loyalist he has recently been appointed
the head of the FBI but they are not
obeying him you see it's just like the
chance VC of the
jnu so the the
commander is one person the commander
wants things to be done but the foot
soldiers are refusing to
obey so that's the problem you face and
that's the problem we are facing in
India um you know the the the vice
Chancellor of jnu has these views but
all the staff all the academic staff
they have other views in India it takes
much longer to change things you know um
once you are a government employee and
you get a job in a government University
for example you have a job for life you
can't be sacked so these people are
there forever essentially as long as
they they are not retired they'll be in
power the foot soldiers the academic
staff the the professors and the
teachers and so on they all have these
leftist views and you cannot legally
fire them otherwise they'll take you to
court and then there's going to be a
whole new Fiasco yeah so that's why it's
going to take long time in India
everything takes time in this country
and that's why the country doesn't
progress fast and that's why we get left
behind so the problem is this the
commander wants things to change but the
foot soldiers don't want it to change So
eventually we have to replace all the
Foot Soldiers with good people right now
they're all rotten most of them at least
that's the
problem okay
V sorry vishar Chan says should I pursue
an MC master's degree in astronomy from
a newer newer IIT or a MC in physics
from a prestigious IIT considering
long-term career opportunities and
research prospects in astronomy look how
many jobs do we have worldwide for
astronomers people who look into
telescopes and look at stars planets
blah blah blah very few there are very
few jobs for astronomers in the world
very few job job openings in India Next
To None how many astronomical
observatories do we have in India very
few very few so it's going to be very
hard for you to get a job in astronomy
as an astronomer once you get your
degree in astronomy that's just the sad
fact maybe you love astronomy you know I
used to love astronomy as a kid I still
do I love all that but you know to be
practical you will have much
more opportunities job opportunities Etc
if you have an if a master's degree in
physics because physics has so many
applications including in technology
engineering and so on if you have MSE in
physics you can Branch out into any lots
of different fields so I would say from
a practical realistic perspective you
should go for your msse in physics not
for an MSE in astronomy just my
suggestion because you
asked um
manuk Krishna says will Zoroastrianism
make a comeback in Iran I here many
people are conver are reverting back to
original persan culture or becoming
atheist right now I think a very
significant percentage of the population
in Persia in Iran is atheist people have
become atheists uh I'm sure many of them
would like to become zoroastrians
zoroastrians Zoros which is their
original kind of original
religion um but they don't know how to
they don't know how to they don't know
what are the precepts of of the religion
how what how the rituals are done and so
on that's why they are simply choosing
to become
atheists um maybe I would say they can
connect with their with with our
zoroastrians in India we still have I
don't know how many 40 50,000 Zoran in
India um so maybe the the Persians can
reconnect with their long lost far away
distant relatives who live in India and
maybe they can revive Zoroastrianism it
would be nice if that happens it would
be
nice okay uh let us take some questions
um I have more questions from the
comments but I'll take some questions
from the live chat as always that's the
tradition
here
um okay what do we
have
um B CH G says how to study Higher
Education Without English and that's the
problem you can't right now in India if
you want high quality higher education
it's going to be in English right so
even if you want to do it in your mother
tongue it's going to be very difficult
for you probably you won't get the
option and that's the problem why don't
we give people options to do what they
want and why don't we discriminate based
on the language you have studied in we
need to reform the education system we
have to rationalize it but we're not
doing it so
yeah that's the problem you can't right
now that's that's the problem that's the
issue
um okay what next do we
have um KJ Wonder says when will the
next understanding America episode come
next week next Thursday it's coming yeah
it's been a slightly delayed thing but
it's going to get back on track from
next week onwards So yeah thank you for
watching I appreciate
that
um okay what else um
mclen says what's the Fifth Dimension
saw Interstellar recently if you watch
Interstellar that there's this concept
of the Tesseract right uh at the end
when the guy I forget his name he dives
into the black hole and apparently it's
a portal to a different place and all
that and there he enters a tesseract
which is a four-dimensional structure or
five dimensional structure what is it is
a tesseract four dimensional F
Tesseract Tesseract is four dimens
so look in in general relativity we have
four dimensions length breadth height
and time those are the four four
dimensions in general relativity and in
interstellar they describe a
four-dimensional structure which we
can't really visualize a fifth see The
Fifth Dimension is hypothetical we don't
we have never observed any Dimensions
Beyond four but you can construct
theories of physics using five
Dimensions it's called the kuta Klein
Theory and yeah it's very interesting
actually it it um it throws some very
interesting
insights in in the Rel in the
relationship between electromagnetism
and gravity it's called kuta clein
Theory and then you have String Theory
which is 10 Dimensions 11 Dimensions you
even have 26 Dimension bosonic string
theory and so on so the Fifth Fifth
Dimension is simply a mathematical
construct uh with the and it's done with
the objective of trying to figure out
the workings of the Universe better so
yeah if you're interested you can look
look into let me just Google it for you
and put that on the screen it's called
kaluta Klein Theory let me put that on
the screen very
quickly five dimensional space time
kaluta client Theory there you have it
all right Fifth Dimension there you have
it so check it out if you are interested
um okay um what other question
see when you are doing question trying
to get questions from the live chat it's
not always easy to find the right
questions um okay madav Sharma says
which country is best if you want to
become a scientist in a foreign country
the US no question about it the
US um okay
[Laughter]
Grim zad says do you think Trump shouts
at Modi the same way he did with
zilinsky in the back doors I don't think
so I'm sure they have tough discussions
I'm sure there will be elements of what
you could call arm
twisting I'm sure there'll be threats I
can fund Pakistan I can get Pakistan to
do this I can lift the restrictions on
Pakistan F16 and the kill switch and and
so on so forth there can be all kinds of
threats but I don't think there is any
shouting because Mr Modi is the kind of
person who knows how to conduct these
things with dignity he
knows diplomacy really well he knows how
to uh how to interact with somebody like
President Donald Trump he knows what Mr
Trump likes what he wants what he needs
and he Mr Modi also knows that there's
no point trying to be obsin obstinate
with with Mr Trump because Trump will
get what he wants because he has so much
leverage so you have to find you have to
do your homework and do the negotiations
diplomacy in a way that is as much
winwin as possible as much M mutually
beneficial as possible and I don't think
Trump is out there to extract every
last you know every every last drop of
juice out of India he's not an unfair
person yeah he wants wins and he wants
to remind every nation that I am greater
I'm bigger I'm stronger I'm better but I
don't think he's out to destroy Every
Nation so I don't think there is that
sort of shouting
and and the sort of disgraceful Behavior
ever between Mr Trump and Mr Modi there
will be disagreements but you can
address and approach disagreements in a
tactful
manner that's what Mr zinski doesn't
understand so I don't think it's that
way at all I'm sure there is tough
negotiations no question but I don't
think there's any shouting on any such
thing because if that happens then when
they come out for the press conference
you will see some strain between them
which is never there so I'm pretty sure
it's it doesn't happen that way and
that's because of the way Mr Modi does
his diplomacy and ensures that all the
homework is done before there a meeting
with Mr
Trump
[Laughter]
okay Karan alwat says which professions
are expected to be successful in the
future and remain largely insulated from
AI impacts long-term nothing right now
yeah if you're a carpenter if you're a
plumber if you're a mechanic if you do
uh engineering work if you construct
highways and so on yeah you may be
insulated from AI impact but eventually
robots will take up all these things
eventually it's going to be very hard to
predict
what what will be insulated which fields
which professions will stay insulated
from a I think nothing eventually in the
next 20 years will be insulated from AI
we'll have to wait and watch uh yeah
that's that's a pretty complicated
question actually but I think it's right
now all bets are
off okay I'm gonna end the live stream
right here thank you so much um I answer
this question in the very beginning John
why don't you take questions from the
live chat nowadays it's because in the
live chat it's not easy for me to find
the really good questions when I take
questions from the comments I can pick
and choose the best questions that are
the most relevant to this week what's
happening in the world right now and
questions that hopefully I haven't
answered before and the question that
will give the best value to the audience
in the live chat I will you know all
questions are good I I have no issue
with people asking simple questions I'm
always happy to answer questions but
most of these questions I have asked I
have answered before so I don't want to
repeat you know repeatedly answer the
same question over and over again like
when are we taking back po or whatever
you know so that's why I take questions
from the
comments and yeah once in a while I
should still do uh live streams in in
which I take questions from the live
chat also but it's about giving the best
value to the audience that's why all
right and with that we will end this
live stream so thank you so much for all
your questions very interesting live
stream very interesting questions and we
shall continue this next week until then
take care keep raising your standards
keep asking questions and I'll see you
very soon next week bye